moment, evidently in order to drink a toast.
A large jug was circulating, and the mugs were being refilled with beer.
No one noticed the wondering faces of the animals that gazed in at the window.
Mr. Pilkington of Foxwood had stood up, his mug in his hand.
In a moment, he said, he would ask the present company to drink a toast.
But before doing so, there were a few words that he felt it incumbent upon him to say.
It was a source of great satisfaction to him, he said, and he was sure to all
others present, to feel that a long period of mistrust and misunderstanding
had now come to an end.
There had been a time, not that he or any of the present company had shared such sentiments,
but there had been a time when the respected proprietors of Animal Farm had been regarded,
he would not say with hostility, but perhaps with a certain measure of
misgiving by their human neighbors.
Unfortunate incidents had occurred.
Mistaken ideas had been current.
It had been felt that the existence of a farm owned and operated by pigs was somehow abnormal,
and was liable to have an unsettling effect in the neighborhood.
Too many farmers had assumed, without due inquiry, that on such a farm a spirit of license
and indiscipline would prevail.
They had been nervous about the effects upon their own animals
or even upon their human employees.
But all such doubts were now dispelled.
Today, he and his friends had visited Animal Farm and inspected every inch of
it with their own eyes.
And what did they find?
Not only the most up-to-date methods, but a discipline and an orderliness
which should be an example to all farmers everywhere.
He believed that he was right in saying that the lower animals on Animal Farm
did more work and received less food than any animals in the county.
Indeed, he and his fellow visitors today had observed many features which they
intended to introduce on their own farms immediately.
He would end his remarks, he said, by emphasizing once again the friendly
feelings that subsisted and ought to subsist between Animal Farm and its neighbors.
Between pigs and human beings, there was not and there need not be
any clash of interests whatever.
Their struggles and their difficulties were one.
Was not the labor problem the same everywhere?
Here, it became apparent that Mr.
Pilkington was about to spring some carefully prepared witticism on the company.
But for a moment, he was too overcome by amusement to be able to utter it.
After much choking, during which his various chins turned purple, he managed to get it out.
>> If you have your lower animals to contend with, we have our lower classes.
>> This bon mot set the table in a roar.
And Mr. Pilkington once again congratulated the pigs on the low
rations, the long working hours, and the general absence of pampering, which he
had observed on Animal Farm.
"And now," he said finally, he would ask the company to rise to their feet
and make certain that their glasses were full.
>> "Gentlemen," >> concluded Mr. Pilkington.
>> "Gentlemen, I give you a toast to the prosperity of Animal Farm."
>> There was enthusiastic cheering and stamping of feet.
Napoleon was so gratified that he left his place and came round the table to
clink his mug against Mr. Pilkington's before emptying it.
When the cheering had died down, Napoleon, who had remained on his feet,